Tim Halliday

Full-Stack Developer

I am a web developer with strong technical and interpersonal skills, having also worked as a teacher and managed teams of freelancers. In my first role as a developer, I have worked highly independently and have quickly acquired a solid foundation in web development.

Work Experience



Web Developer Britcent (Online English education company)

April 2022 - Present (1 year, 5 months)

- Independently developed a web app for the English learning community that automated time consuming processes to now generate approximately 15% of total company revenue.
- Built diagnostic dashboards to illustrate financial health and inform important business decisions.
- Provided paternity cover for the senior developer, acting as the main point of contact for the tech team.
- Designed and developed a mini web app that allowed tutors to share English learning materials with students, improving teacher-student relationships and customer satisfaction.
- Integrated APIs for messaging, email subscriber lists and payment systems, including Stripe.
- Implemented unit testing where this did not exist before.

English Tutor and Editor

Britcent (Online English education company) January 2020 - January 2021 (2 years)

- Independently planned and taught one-on-one English lessons over Zoom, building confidence and initiative.
- Developed communication skills and the ability to explain complex concepts in an accessible way.

SEO Copywriter

Adapt Worldwide

April 2018 - January 2020 (6 months full-time/ 15 months freelance)

- Wrote SEO-optimised content to boost web traffic for a wide variety of clients, from financial to retail sectors.
- Developed a good knowledge of SEO best practices and how to generate clicks with this.

Contact Info

<u>(+44) 07549589903</u> <u>thalliday793@gmail.com</u>

timhalliday.co.uk github.com/timhalliday linkedin.com/in/timothyhalliday

Key Skills

- Java 8
- Spring Boot
- JQuery
- Javascript ES6
- HTML5
- CSS3
- React
- Bootstrap
- AWS
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MyBatis
- Ruby/Rails

Languages

- French & Spanish (professional proficiency)
- Portuguese (conversational)
- German (basics)

Education History

Coding Bootcamp - Le Wagon London, Batch #207 (2022)

- 9-week intensive coding bootcamp learning HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, SQL, git, Git, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.
- Built a language-learning app as a team, using pair programming and git for version control.
- MSc Language Sciences UCL (Distinction) With research project into stuttering using R for

data analysis.

 BA French/Spanish with Japanese -University of Exeter (First class honours)